PRATHEESH FRANCIS

Mob D: +918129169536

E-mail : pratheeshfrancis2008@gmail.com

Address ⊠: **TVM, Kerala, India.**



Profile Summary

Highly competent accounting professional with 7+ years of extensive functional experience in finance and general management within diversified industries. Expertise within the spheres of financial accounting, analysis, accounts reconciliation, cost control, payroll, VAT, cash management and client relations including multinational companies. Motivated and committed employee who can contribute to core business activities with proven abilities in the team, promptly resolving problems and maximizing levels of productivity plus strong communication, organizational, coordination and time management skills. Proficient in accounting packages and MS office applications.

Strengths & Competencies

- 7+ years of professional work experience.
- Flexible and ability to work under pressure.
- Effective work management and multitasking.
- Excellent communication skills.

- Knowledge in VAT(UAE Tax)
- Commitment to on-going professional development.
- Proficient in ERP system and MS Office.
- Strong analytical, Mathematical and accounting skills.

Career Snapshot

•Accounts Executive- Blue Marine Fisheries LLC, Ajman, UAE	June 2015	- Feb 2020
• Assistant Accountant- World Link Technical Contracting LLC, Sharjah, UAE	April 2013	- April 2015
• MIT-Wagamama LTD- London, UK	Nov 2009	- Feb 2013
• Assistant Accountant- Bajaj Allianz and Insurance Co. Ltd- India	Jan 2009	- July 2009

Educational Qualification

Masters in Business Administration(in Marketing and Finance)	April 2011
University of Sunderland, London, UK.	
B-Tec in Advanced Professional Diploma in Management Studies	Jan 2010
Edexcel Level 7-Ethames College, London,UK	
Bachelor of Commerce with Computer Application	April 2008
University of Kerala, India	

Professional Experiences

1. Blue Marine Fisheries LLC as Accounts Executive

June 2015 - Feb 2020

- Prepare profit and loss statements and monthly closing reports.
- Compile and analyze financial information to prepare entries to accounts, such as general ledger accounts, and document business transactions.
- Maintain, and coordinate the implementation of accounting and accounting control procedures.
- Analyze and review budgets and expenditures for local and private funding, contracts, and grants.
- Assists in preparation of monthly management report and accompanying schedules, worksheets and narratives, including "Budget vs. Actual" variance reports.
- Assist in providing follow-up and documentation of significant variances.
- Assist with completion of the quarterly and annual regulatory filings of Tax; preparation of assigned Quarterly and Annual Statutory Statement.
- Delivering VAT reporting, ensuring VAT compliance and identifying risk.
- Calculating output and input tax.
- Assist in preparing assigned schedules for the annual external and interim audit. Banking/Cash:
- Coordinate and resolve various issues with bank such as cleared check differences, bank fee anomalies, targeted balance calculations and enhancements to online services. Monitor positive pay exceptions.
- Handling petty cash for daily operation.
- Auditing and reimbursing petty cash on regularly.
- Performed payroll functions of more than 200+ employees.
- Controlled and maintained accounts payable and receivable functions.
- Functioned in for the company's all the government policies and requirements.

2. Wold Link Tech. Contracting LLC as Assistant Accountant.

April 2013 - April 2015

- Performed account payable function
- Managed financial department with responsibility for Budgets, Forecasting, Payroll, Accounts Payable and \receivable.
- Ensured compliance with accounting deadlines.
- Coordinate monthly payroll function for 150+ employees.
- Liaised with bankers, insurers and solicitors regarding financial transactions.
- Administrated online banking function.
- Monitored and recorded company expenses.

3. Wagamama Ltd (London, UK Team) as Manager in Trainee.

Nov 2009 – Feb 2013

- Underwent all the placing process for the fresh candidates.
- Given first hand training for the selected employees.
- Preparing, collecting, recording and analysing performance appraisal on timely basis.
- In charge with assigning weekly rota for all the employees and made sure keep the hours with in the budgeted cost.
- Recording and updated the time sheet in to the ERP system.
- Analysing the sales performance on timely basis and reporting that in to top level management.
- Checking and finalising all the expenses and invoices bills.

4. Bajaj Allianz and Insurance Co. Ltd (India) as **Assistant Accountant** Jan - April 2007

- Handled daily data entries, income/sales reports, sales receipt and bank account transactions.
- Coded payables/receivable produced invoice and assisted in preparing monthly financial reports.
- Performed various routine adjustments to company documentation records and logs.
- Double checked accounting reports, verified invoices and various documents for accuracy.
- Balanced entries, organised documents, debits and credits.
- Performed salary entry and documentation.
- Balance sheet reconciliation.
- Reconciling petty cash.

IT Skills

✓ Application : Diploma in Computer Application(MS Word, MS Excel)

✓ Software : Tally 7.2 and 9, Daceasy, Wings, Peachtree Accounting

Personal Details

• Date Of Birth : 25/05/1988 • Marital Status : Married

• Nationality : Indian • Place of Birth : TVM, Kerala

• Languages Known : English, Hindi,

Malayalam, Tamil